so anna we did two lessons so far we did
one on the forehand backhand and the
serve we did one on the valley
and today we're gonna do something super
important and it's called rallying
you know yeah you know what rallying is
okay a lot of people confuse
volleying with rallying so they'll say
oh let's volley back and forth to each
other meaning that they're going to keep
the ball in play but that's the wrong
term the actual term for keeping the
ball in play hitting it back and forth
to each other is rallying so that's what
we're going to do today we're going to
try to hit back and forth to each other
when you learn to rally you're going to
also be able to play with other people
which is going to be very important and
so what you got to watch out for when
you're rallying
is number one being in your ready
position that we learned so when you're
waiting for the ball
a lot of people have a tendency to kind
of stand around on their heels
and kind of straight up and then when
the ball comes they're not ready to move
because let's face it the ball it's not
going to come right to you it's going to
be all over the place and you'll have to
go get it so you have to be ready to
move your feet and watch the ball very
carefully another common thing when the
beginner level players start to rally is
that they panic so what they do is
they're waiting for the ball and the
ball comes and then they
right away try to take a swing at it
they swing right away and now
they're not set up properly they're not
timing the ball properly
and because they're swinging super fast
they're not executing the proper
technique so i want you to remember to
use the correct sequence
this is something that we talked about
in our first lesson which is go in a
ready position and now
the first thing you're going to do is
observe the incoming ball while you are
in a ready position so let's assume it
goes to the forehand
the first thing you do is make a turn
towards your forehand side okay and then
you also change the grip and find the
forehand grip and now
you set up the forehand and then once
you find that you're set up in the most
accurate place
then you think about hitting the ball so
hitting is going to be the third step
we're going to try
to rally volleys first because those are
the easiest ones to rally so go ahead
and stand at the net right here so right
now i want you to do forehand valleys
first just to get used to
the tempo of the rally come on up a
little closer
and set the racket on the side already
like this go a little higher with the
racket just put it right here bend the
arm
in front and uh yeah and now i'm gonna
hit the ball
and you're just gonna tap it back right
to me okay
good good and just kind of track the
ball and come right back to me
good all right
are we doing it now remember we talked
about you want to be in an athletic
position because look if i go here
you're not ready if you're straight up
you're fine if it's coming to you
you have to be in an athletic position
let's do it again
okay you come right at me here we go
good
wow no no no for now we're just doing
forehand so you don't have to worry
about switching
all right we're going to do both in a
second
good and again
let's try to go up to ten three i'm only
counting your hits four
five six seven
eight nine and ten all right what do you
think
it's fun right see this is the real
tennis okay going back and forth
let's try backhand same thing one
two three four
five six seven
eight nine wow
ten in a row that's very impressive okay
now we do
ten in a row random so you don't know
where it's coming so you're gonna have
to go from the ready position
one two three
oh you missed it okay so this is going
to be a lot harder than the other way
around because
this is the difficulty about rallying is
that you don't know where the ball is
coming
and this is where you have to apply the
sequencing okay so you have to be calm
and not to rush even though the ball is
coming quickly make sure you see the
ball first before you make a decision
like don't go to the back end without
knowing that the ball is going to go to
your backhand side never takes you
anywhere anyways
absolutely one oh
that was too low come again one
two all right here we go one
two three four
five six
seven eight nice good
nine match points all right
yes very good what did you think that
was pretty easy right it was fun
you got 10 in a row pretty fast very
nice job so now let's try to rally
forehands and backhands
and we're going to do it from the
service line first so the important
antennas is that you
in the beginning when you first start to
hit back and forth is that you do it
very gently and slowly
if you hit it hard you're not going to
be able to keep the ball in play and
then gradually over time you start
adding
speed
nice
okay
go go go come on come on come on this is
different than what we did here
this is like our first lesson that we
had is our forehands and backhands
ground strokes right okay so so a couple
of things i want to tell you
yes remember our lesson we kind of
started short here
and then we made sure we finished all
the way applied exactly the same
fundamentals
to the rally and the most important
thing is that you finish because a lot
of beginner players are very
cautious about finishing so they hit the
ball and they kind of stop here or
they're very careful in this area and
it's very difficult to control
the ball that way good
nice okay i'm still gonna keep score
okay that's three
four five
six seven
eight nine
ten okay so now you do the exact same
thing but you're gonna hit it to this
corner where i'm standing okay and you
can do it from the middle
right there so go ready position we'll
try to do ten in a row
okay that's no good it's gotta come back
to me
go again one
two
three
okay that was a little bit too far to
the middle so we're learning now is
directional control so you can see when
you hit the ball a little bit late or
behind you it's very hard to get it that
way right
it kind of goes towards the middle so
it's important that you play the ball in
front a little more
okay one
two
three
four five
go go go six
seven
eight nine
ten yes we do the same thing now to this
side you hit everything back to me okay
here we go one
two
three
okay that's a one-handed backhand you
always try to play with two hands okay
one
okay i'll give it to you two
actually that's four i miscounted here's
five
okay six
good seven
eight
nine
not the match point let's start over
one two
three four
five six
seven
eight
okay i'll give it to you nine and match
points
all right very good wow fantastic job so
you got 10 in a row
in the three different ways down the
middle you got it to the side and the
other side you know the fascinating
thing
about it is that you already are
learning directional to control you're
learning how to
aim antennas so now let's make it a
little bit harder i'm gonna do the
ultimate test with you let's try to
rally
from the baseline and obviously you're
gonna have to hit it a little bit harder
here
one
one two
back up a little bit back it up
three four
five six
seven eight
no you hit it way too hard try again we
need ten okay
ten balls
one two
three take your time come on four
five six
seven
eight nine
you know what was funny on that second
last attempt you got so confident you
started hitting hard eight
no but then you paid the price because
you missed one what's gonna happen is
you're gonna
start hitting hard and overheating and
making mistakes so you have to always
remind yourself that the most important
thing right now
in your tennis is control this is how
you're going to build the correct muscle
memory
and you're going to build the confidence
to hit harder very gradually over time
all right so the final test for today is
i'm actually going to go on the baseline
we're going to rally
baseline to baseline because when i'm
rallying with you from the net i'm
giving you a really clean
valley and the ball is coming kind of
low and flat
but now i'm going to go on a baseline
it's going to be a little bit more
difficult okay let's
let's go for 10 okay come on
one
two
three
four
five
six
seven one
eight no again
one
two
three
four
five
six
seven
eight
nine match point
really really good job again this is not
normal that someone progresses this fast
to be able to keep the ball in play
so you have a lot of natural ability for
tennis and i really encourage you to
keep playing all right good job let's do
a you don't have a racket here let's do
a tap with a bottle a bottle tap
all right very nice good job very nice
that was good it was fun right
okay let's go back by the way you're
playing so well people think it's fake
i have a couple of comments saying that
it's fake that you're not a beginner
yeah i have a
what is it beginner's luck you're very
talented